Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Organizations PE.036
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Organizations
1865-2019
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
Gluck, Sidney
Tress, Madeline
Filardo, Peter
PE.036
129.5 Linear Feet in 121 record cartons, 9 manuscript boxes, and 11 shared boxes
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Organizations (1865-2019), an artificial collection of vertical files, was accumulated gradually over the years as staff set aside ephemera that was relevant to Tamiment Library's collecting focus but did not belong in discreet collections. This collection consists of brochures, bulletins, catalogs, flyers, clippings, leaflets, manifestoes, pamphlets, press releases, programs, and other printed ephemera created by or related to organizations connected with the labor movement, trade unionism, radical politics, feminism, civil rights, and other movements.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
Collection is organized into 27 series; one for titles starting with numerals, and one for each letter of the alphabet. Files are arranged alphabetically by file title.
Series are arranged alphabetically.
Custodial History
The provenance of the materials is varied. Items were obtained through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, arrangements with labor unions and other organizations, exchanges with other libraries, and ongoing collecting by Tamiment staff.
Historical Note
The Tamiment Library, New York University, a special collection documenting the history of United States radicalism, labor, and progressive social action, accumulated this artificial collection of printed ephemera gradually over the years through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, trade unions and other organizations, and through exchanges with other special library collections via the Collectors' Network, which was organized by Russell Benedict at the University of Nevada in the 1970s and promoted through his newsletter Top Secret. Tamiment Library staff added materials to this collection on a regular basis.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Individuals (PE 030)
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Subjects (PE 029)
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Trade Unions (PE 001)
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection of Oversized Material (PE 040)
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Organizations (1865-2019) is composed of printed ephemera related to the primary collecting areas of the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives: Leftist politics and Labor history. This collection includes files created by or related to organizations that were of a part of or of interest to members of the political Left in the United States. Organizations represented are political parties, anti-war protest movements, legal associations, and student groups, and are leftist or radical in nature. Examples, including the Black Panthers, Workers' Defense League, American Labor Party, Social Democratic Federation of America, and New England Free Press, demonstrate the depth and variety of this collection. These organizations are documented by broadsides, brochures, bulletins, catalogs, clippings, flyers, leaflets, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, posters, press releases, programs, and other printed ephemera arranged alphabetically by organization.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this collection have been compiled by the Tamiment Library.
Some materials were donated by Madeline Tress in 1988 and by Sidney Gluck in 2004. There are no accession records associated with these materials.
Various materials were found in the repository in 2014 and added to this collection. The accession numbers associated with this material are 2014.021, 2014.030, 2014.036, 2014.058, 2014.065, and 2014.078.
Accession numbers also associated with this collection are NPA.2000.260, NPA.2001.034, NPA.2001.070, and NPA.2001.093.
In 2021, an accretion of materials collected by Everett Allgood, Authorities Librarian and Principal Serials Cataloger at NYU Libraries, and Shannon O'Neill, Curator for Tamiment-Wagner Collections, was added to this collection. The accession number with this accretion is 2021.019.
In 2025, materials from accession 2019.056, which is associated with Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Subjects (PE 029), were transferred to this collection.
Trotskyism.; Women's rights -- United States.; Radicalism -- United States.; Socialism; Anarchism.; Anti-communist movements; Brochures.; Bulletins.; Circular letters.; Civil rights -- United States.; Civil rights.; Communism.; Political activists -- United States.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements -- United States.; Peace movements -- United States.; Pamphlets.; Clippings (information artifacts); Fliers (printed matter); Labor movement -- United States.; Draft resisters; Gay rights -- United States.; Youth movements -- United States.; Printed ephemera.; Demonstrations -- United States.; Feminism -- United States.; War resistance movements -- United States.; Gay liberation movement -- United States.; Gluck, Sidney; Tress, Madeline; Filardo, Peter; International Labor Defense; International Socialist Organization (U.S.); International Workers Order; American Civil Liberties Union; American Labor Party; Liberal Party of New York State; Fourth Internationalist Tendency (Group); Farmer-Labor Party (Minn.); International Socialists (U.S.); Congress of Racial Equality; Black Panther Party; American Friends Service Committee; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.); War Resisters League; World Peace Council; Social Democratic Federation of America; Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (U.S.); Jefferson School of Social Science (New York, N.Y.); National Council of American-Soviet Friendship (U.S.); New England Free Press; Progressive Labor Party; Rand School of Social Science; Worker's Defense League
- Numeric, 1967-2010; 1.5 Linear Feet in 1 record carton and 1 manuscript box
  - 1freeworld.org, 2003 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - 9 to 5 National Association of Working Women, 1982-1992, undated (Box 1)
  - 9/11 Truth, undated (Box 1)
  - 9th War Wallace for President Committee, undated (Box 1)
  - 12th Avenue Space (New York, NY), undated (Box 1)
    Historical Note
    12th Avenue Space facilitated workshops on reclaiming public space.
  - 12th Street For Peace, 1968 (Box 1)
  - 17th C.D. Peace Action Committee, 1967 (Box 1)
  - 123 Community Space (Brooklyn, NY), 2009- (Box 1)
  - 180 Movement for Democracy and Education, undated (Box 1)
  - 350 Reasons, 2010- (Box 1)
  - 50 Years Is Enough (Organization), 2002-2005 (Box 1)
    50 Years is Enough was an organization focused on reforming the World Bank and International Monetary Fund.
- A, 1891-2012; 13.75 Linear Feet in 13 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, and 1 oversize shared box
  - A16 Medical Team, undated (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - A. Philip Randolph Education Fund I, 1968-1981, undated (Box 1)
  - A. Philip Randolph Education Fund II, 1968-1981, undated (Box 1)
  - A. Philip Randolph Institute, 1965-1969 (Box 1)
  - A. Philip Randolph Institute, 1970-1999 (Box 1)
  - A. Philip Randolph Institute, undated (Box 1)
  - ABC Cuba, 1932 (Box 1)
  - ABC No Rio, 2007- (Box 1)
  - Aberdeen Solidarity Pamphlets, circa 1970s (Box 1)
  - Abolish the Bank, 2002, undated (Box 1)
  - Abortion Action Coalition, undated (Box 1)
  - Abortion Rights Action Week, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Abraham Lincoln School (Chicago, IL), 1944-1945, undated (Box 1)
  - Accra Assembly (Ghana): The World without the Bomb, 1962 (Box 1)
  - ACT (Neighborhood Organization) (Durham, NC), 1969 (Box 1)
  - ACT UP (AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power), undated (Box 1)
  - Action Books, undated (Box 1)
  - Action for Women in Chile (New York, NY), undated (Box 1)
  - Action Forum Against Star Wars Agenda, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Active Thought Project, undated (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - Activists for a Democratic Culture, undated (Box 1)
  - Activists for Independent Socialist Politics (AISP) (Berkeley, CA), 1992-1994 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Abortion Conference Committee, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Citizens Committee for Community Control, undated (Box 1, Box 122, Folder 6)
  - Ad Hoc Committee Against Racist Immigration Laws, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Ad-hoc Committee Against the Interstate Highway, undated (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - Ad Hoc Committee for a Marxist-Leninist Party USA, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee for a Revolutionary Contingent, undated (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee for a True University (Boston University), circa 1978 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee for Jobs and Peace (New York, NY), 1986 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee for Lining the Route, undated (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee for Peace in the Middle East (London, U.K.), undated (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee of Lawyers for Justice, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on the Triple Revolution, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Vietnam Veterans' Week '82, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee to Defend Michel Warchawsky, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee to Demonstrate Against the Budget Cuts, undated (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee to End the War in Vietnam (Cornell University), 1965-1970 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee to Save America, 1969 (Box 1, Box 122, Folder 7)
  - Ad Hoc Committee to Save Wayne Felde, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Group for American Anarchism, undated (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc National Network to Stop Foreclosures and Evictions, 2008- (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Strike Support Committee (Harvard University), undated (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Student Committee on Viet Nam, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Summer Vietnam Project of the 13th C.D., undated (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Veterans' Committee for Memorial Day Peace Action, undated (Box 1)
  - Ada World Magazine, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Cylinder and Web Press Printers' Association, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Advance Co-operative Publishing Company, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Advance (New York, NY), 1961, undated (Box 1)
  - Advisory Council on Church and Society, undated (Box 1)
  - Advocates, The, undated (Box 1)
  - Aesthetic Realism Foundation (New York, NY), 1997, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Affiliated Schools for Workers I, 1930-1934 (Box 1)
  - Affiliated Schools for Workers II, 1930-1934 (Box 1)
  - Affiliated Schools for Workers I, 1935-1939 (Box 1)
  - Affiliated Schools for Workers II, 1935-1939 (Box 1)
  - Affiliated Schools for Workers, undated (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action Coordinating Center, 1979, undated (Box 1)
  - Africa League, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Africa Research Group I, 1968-1971, undated (Box 1)
  - Africa Research Group II, 1968-1971, undated (Box 1)
  - Africa World Press: Catalogs, 1997-1999 (Box 1)
  - African-American Labour Centre (Nigeria), 1971 (Box 122, Folder 8)
  - African-American Students Association, 1971 (Box 2)
  - African-American Teachers Association, 1967-1969, undated (Box 2)
  - African Liberation Day Coalition, 1977, 1982 (Box 2)
  - African Liberation Support Committee (Chicago, IL), 1977 (Box 2)
  - African National Prison Organization Solidarity Committee (San Francisco, CA), undated (Box 2)
  - African People's Socialist Party, 1977-1981 (Box 2)
  - African People's Solidarity Committee, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Afro-American Committee, undated (Box 2)
  - Afro-American Heritage Association, undated (Box 2)
  - Afro-Asian Council, undated (Box 2)
  - Afro-Asian Journalists' Association, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Afro-Asian Solidarity Committee of the German Democratic Republic, 1966, undated (Box 2)
  - Afro-Asian Writers' Bureau, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Afro-Asian Youth Movement, undated (Box 2)
    The Afro-Asian Youth Movement was an anti-imperialist organization.
  - After the Fall, undated (Box 2)
  - Aftershock Action Alliance, 2009- (Box 2)
  - Against the Current, 1988 (Box 2, Box 122, Folder 9)
  - Against the Wall (Organization), undated (Box 2)
  - Agenda for Non-Collaboration (Chicago, IL), 1984, undated (Box 2)
  - Agenda Publishing Co., 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Agent Orange Victims of New Jersey, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Agrarian Party of Greece, circa 1949 (Box 2)
  - Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectual, Inc. (New York, NY), undated (Box 2)
  - AK Press, undated, 2012 (Box 2)
  - Akwesasne Notes/ Mohawk Nation, 1980, undated (Box 2)
  - Alabama Christian Movement for Human Rights (Birmingham, AL), 1962-1966 (Box 2)
  - Alexander Defense Committee (New York, NY), 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Algerian National Liberation Front (Jabhat Al-Tahrir Al-Qawmi), 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - Algic Defense Committee (New York, NY), undated (Box 2)
  - Alive Production Collective (Ontario, Canada), 1975, undated (Box 2)
  - All-African Peoples Union, 1974 (Box 2)
  - All-African People's Revolutionary Party, undated (Box 2)
  - All-American Conference to Combat Communism, 1974 (Box 2)
  - All-Campus Peace Council, 1937 (Box 2)
  - All China Democratic Women's Federation, 1952 (Box 2)
  - All-China Federation of Democratic Youth, 1952-1953, undated (Box 2)
  - All-China Union, circa 1936 (Box 2)
  - All-People's Congress (New York, NY), 1983-1985, undated (Box 2)
  - All People's Party (Harlem, New York, NY), undated (Box 2)
  - Allegheny Worker Group (Pittsburgh, PA), 1958 (Box 2)
  - Alliance Des Jeunes Pour Le Socialisme, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Alliance for Democracy, 1999-2005, undated (Box 2)
  - Alliance for Jobs or Income Now (New York, NY), undated (Box 2)
  - Alliance for Workers' Liberty/ Workers' Liberty Pamphlets I, 1987-2002, undated (Box 2)
  - Alliance for Workers' Liberty/ Workers' Liberty Pamphlets II, 1987-2002, undated (Box 2)
  - Alliance of Revolutionary Workers (Seattle, WA), 1973, undated (Box 2)
  - Alliance Party (Philadelphia, PA), undated (Box 2)
  - Allied Artists of America, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Allied Council of Employed and Unemployed Citizens of Colorado, circa 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - Allied Media Conference, 2009- (Box 2)
  - Alternative Features Service (Berkeley, CA), 1971 (Box 2)
  - Alternative Media Information Center, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Alternative Perspectives on Vietnam (Organization) (Ann Arbor, MI), 1965 (Box 2)
  - Alternative Press Centre (Toronto, Canada), 1973 (Box 2)
  - Alternative Press Syndicate (New York, NY), 1976, undated (Box 2)
  - Alternative Radio (Boulder, CO), 1999-2002 (Box 2)
  - Alternative Revenue Service (New York, NY), 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - Alternative U, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Box 122, Folder 10)
  - Alternatives! Foundation (San Francisco, CA), circa 1970 (Box 2)
  - Amerasia (New York, NY), 1942, 1947 (Box 2)
  - America First Committee, 1940-1941 (Box 2)
  - American Academic Association for Peace in the Middle East, 1972 (Box 2)
  - American Afro-Asian Education Service, 1957-1963 (Box 2)
  - American Alliance for Labor and Democracy, 1917, undated (Box 2)
  - American Anarchist Magazine (San Francisco, CA), 1964 (Box 2)
  - American Anarchist Federated Commune Soviets, 1925 (Box 2)
  - American Anti-Boycott Association, undated (Box 2)
  - American Anti-Imperialist League, 1899 (Box 2)
  - American Anti-Trust League (Washington, DC), 1899 (Box 2)
  - American Anti-Wage-Slavery Society (New York, NY), 1910 (Box 2)
  - American Anti-War Crusade, circa 1940s (Box 2)
  - American Appeal (Chicago, IL), undated (Box 2)
  - American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee I, 1981-1989, undated (Box 2)
  - American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee II, 1981-1989, undated (Box 2)
  - American Arbitration Association (New York, NY), 1938-1983 (Box 2)
  - American Artists' Congress/ Young Artists and Art Students of the USA, 1936, undated (Box 3)
  - American-Asian Education Exchange (New York, NY), 1958-1970 (Box 3)
  - American Association for a Democratic Germany, undated (Box 3)
  - American Association for Economic Freedom (Washington, DC), 1940-1941 (Box 3)
  - American Association for Labor Legislation I, 1909-1915 (Box 3)
  - American Association for Labor Legislation II, 1909-1915 (Box 3)
  - American Association for Labor Legislation, 1933, undated (Box 3)
  - American Association for Labor Research, 1906-1930, undated (Box 3)
  - American Association for Labor Research: Pamphlets, 1920-1941, undated (Box 3)
  - American Association for Old Age Security, 1928-1930, undated (Box 3)
  - American Association for Reconstruction in Yugoslavia, 1946 (Box 3)
  - American Association for Social Security, 1935-1942, undated (Box 3)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Atheism, undated (Box 3)
  - American Association of Social Workers, 1935-1945 (Box 3, Box 122, Folder 11)
  - American Association on Unemployment, 1915 (Box 3)
  - American Atheists (Austin, TX), 1978-1983, undated (Box 3)
  - American Bar Association, 1953-1967 (Box 3)
  - American Birobidjan Committee (New York, NY), 1943-1948 (Box 3)
  - American Birth Control League (New York, NY), circa 1941-1947 (Box 3)
  - American Bureau of Industrial Research (Madison, WI), 1904-1907 (Box 3)
  - American Christian Palestine Committee (New York, NY), circa 1940s (Box 3)
  - American Christians Towards Socialism (ACTS), undated (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1920-1929 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1930-1934 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1935-1939 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1940-1944 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1945-1965 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1966- (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, undated (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Boston Branch, 1920 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Chicago Civil Liberties Committee, 1931-1946 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Civil Liberties Committee of Massachusetts, 1943-1950 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Committee on Labor Injunctions, 1931 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Indiana Civil Liberties Union, 1963-1966 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: New York Civil Liberties Union, 1957-1974, 2004-2007, undated (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: New York Civil Liberties Union: Brooklyn Chapter, 1970, undated (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Pamphlets I, 1920-1929 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Pamphlets II, 1920-1929 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Pamphlets I, 1930-1934 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Pamphlets II, 1930-1934 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Pamphlets III, 1930-1934 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Pamphlets I, 1935-1939 (Box 4)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Pamphlets II, 1935-1939 (Box 4)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Pamphlets I, 1940-1944 (Box 4)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Pamphlets II, 1940-1944 (Box 4)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Pamphlets, 1945-1949 (Box 4)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Pamphlets I, 1950-1968 (Box 4)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Pamphlets II, 1950-1968 (Box 4)
  - American Civil Liberties Union: Pamphlets, undated (Box 4)
  - American Coalition, 1934 (Box 4)
  - American Coalition of Patriotic Societies (New York, NY; Washington, DC), 1938-1972 (Box 4)
  - American Committee Against Fascist Oppression in Germany (New York, NY), 1933 (Box 4)
  - American Committee for Aid to Katanga Freedom Fighters, undated (Box 4)
  - American Committee for Christian German Refugees (New York, NY), 1939 (Box 4)
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom, 1952, undated (Box 4)
  - American Committee for Democracy and Freedom in Greece (New York, NY), 1967-1971 (Box 4)
  - American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom (New York, NY), 1939-1941 (Box 4)
  - American Committee for Free Russia, Inc., undated (Box 4)
  - American Committee for Justice to China (New York, NY), 1933 (Box 4)
  - American Committee for Liberation (New York, NY), 1957, undated (Box 4)
  - American Committee for Liberation from Bolshevism (New York, NY), circa 1950s (Box 4)
  - American Committee for Non-Participation in Japanese Aggression (New York, NY), circa 1937-1940 (Box 4)
  - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born I, 1940-1978 (Box 4, Box 122, Folder 12)
  - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born II, 1940-1978 (Box 4)
  - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born III, 1940-1978, undated (Box 4)
  - American Committee for Solidarity with Vietnamese People (San Francisco, CA), 1969, undated (Box 4)
  - American Committee for Struggle Against War (New York, NY), 1932-1933 (Box 4)
  - American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky, 1937 (Box 4)
  - American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky (New York, NY), 1937-1938 (Box 4)
  - American Committee for the Relief of Victimized German Children (New York, NY), undated (Box 4)
  - American Committee for the World Congress Against War, undated (Box 4)
  - American Committee for the Yugoslav Relief Ship (New York, NY), 1945 (Box 4)
  - American Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives (New York, NY), 1943 (Box 4)
  - American Committee on Africa (New York, NY), 1950-1959 (Box 4)
  - American Committee on Africa (New York, NY), 1960-1969 (Box 4)
  - American Committee on Africa (New York, NY), 1970-1989 (Box 4)
  - American Committee on Africa (New York, NY), undated (Box 4)
  - American Committee on Religious Rights and Minorities (New York, NY), 1939 (Box 4)
  - American Committee on a United Europe, 1951 (Box 4)
  - American Committee on War Finance (New York, NY), undated (Box 4)
  - American Committee to Keep Biafra Alive (New York, NY), circa 1968 (Box 4)
  - American Committee to Survey Labor Conditions in Europe, 1951 (Box 4)
  - American Commonwealth Party (Chicago, IL), 1943 (Box 4)
  - American Commonwealth Political Federation (Washington, DC), undated (Box 4)
  - American Continental Congress for World Peace (New York, NY), 1949 (Box 4)
  - American Council for a Democratic Greece (New York, NY), 1948-1949, undated (Box 4)
  - American Council for Freedom in Bahrain, 2012 (Box 4)
  - American Council on Public Affairs (Washington, DC) I, 1937-1941, undated (Box 5)
  - American Council on Public Affairs (Washington, DC) II, 1937-1941, undated (Box 5)
  - American Council on Race Relations, 1947, undated (Box 5)
  - American Council on Soviet Relations (New York, NY) I, 1941-1942, undated (Box 5)
  - American Council on Soviet Relations (New York, NY) II, 1941-1942, undated (Box 5)
  - American Crusade to End Lynching, 1946 (Box 5)
  - American Defense Society (New York, NY), 1918-1925 (Box 5)
  - American Delegation of the General Jewish Workers Union of Poland (New York, NY), circa 1941 (Box 5)
  - American Documentary Films (New York, NY; San Francisco, CA), circa 1970 (Box 5)
  - American Dream Movement, undated (Box 5)
  - American Economic Foundation, 1942-1945 (Box 5)
  - American Federation of Anarchists, undated (Box 5)
  - American Federation of Housing Authorities, 1937 (Box 5)
  - American Federation of Youth, 1926 (Box 5)
  - American Forum for Socialist Education (New York, NY), 1957, undated (Box 5)
  - American Forum of the Air (Radio Program) (Washington, DC), 1939-1951 (Box 5)
  - American Foundation for Abundance, 1940 (Box 5)
  - American Foundation for Continuing Education (Chicago, IL), 1957 (Box 5)
  - American Foundation on Automation and Employment (New York, NY), circa 1962 (Box 5)
  - American Freedom Foundation (Chicago, IL), 1920 (Box 5)
  - American Friends of Aid to Russia, 1944 (Box 5)
  - American Friends of Brazil (Berkeley, CA), 1974, undated (Box 5)